Finding Aid for the Collection of 19th-century European Sheet Music, circa 1791-1900
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Complete works, circa 1791-1900, I.; Items 1-125
  - Jähns, Friedrich Wilhelm, 1809-1888 Zweistimmige Lieder, op. 48 Drei zweistimmige Lieder, 1860, 1 score (15 pages); Berlin (Germany): Schlesinger For mezzo-soprano and baritone with piano. First page notes this edition is for "Alt und Bass (Mezzo-sopran und Bariton)". (Box 2, Item 057)
    No. 1. Ich stand in dunklen Träumen -- No. 2. Ich bin die Rose auf der Au -- No. 3. Es schlief ein Keim unnennbar klein.
  - Jourdan, Philippe Rose verte Rose verte: schottisch, 1865, 1 score (5 pages); Paris (France): Mme. Vve. Launer For piano. "À sa Majesté Isabelle II, Reine d'Espagne". Color title page illustration: a green rose / A. Forget. (Box 2, Item 058)
  - Keller, Karl, 1784-1855 Dances, flute, piano, op. 35 Six danses: quatre walses et deux ländler, op. 35, circa 1833, 2 parts (2 and 5 pages); Berlin (Germany): N. Simrock For piano and flute. Separate piano and flute parts (the flute part does not appear on the piano part). Dedicated to "amateurs de musique agréable". *date could not be determined (Box 2, Item 059)
    Pages 3-8 missing in piano part. Flute part appears complete. Piano part has one movement labelled in the score as No. 1. Ländler. Flute part has six movements labelled in the score as the following: No. 1. Ländler, No. 2. Walzer, No. 3. Walzer, No. 4. Ländler, No. 5. Walzer, and No. 6. Walzer.
  - Köhler, Louis, 1820-1886 Gesänge, op. 6 Gesänge, op. 6, circa 1847, 1 score (9 pages); Berlin (Germany): Schlesinger For voice and piano. Other title: 3 Lieder für Sopran oder Tenor, op. 6 "Begleitung des Piano Herrn Friedrich Schmezer". (Box 2, Item 060)
    Zum Liebchen / Dichtung von B. Gledock -- Ständchen / Dichtung von Roswitha Kind -- Spanische Serenade / Dichtung von R. Gottschall.
  - Lafitte, A. Chanson bachique Chanson Bachique: tirée du Capitaine Fracasse, 1864, 1 score (2 pages); Paris (France): Au Ménestrel For voice and piano. Lyricist: Gautier, Théophile, 1811-1872 First page notes that there are two editions available, "No. 1. Baryton" and "No. 2. Ténor". This edition is for "No. 2. Ténor". Title page illustration: a grape vine, a cup, and a sword illuminating the title / Imp. Maucelot. (Box 2, Item 061)
  - Lefébure-Wély, Louis James Alfred, 1817-1870 Études de salon. Veillée au chateau Veillée au chateau, circa 1846, 1 score (4 pages); Paris (France): L. Grus For piano. "Extrait des Etudes de salon"--bottom margin. (Box 2, Item 062)
    Music bound from tops of the pages.
  - Linter, Ricardo, approximately 1818-1886 Black bird quadrilles Black-bird quadrilles, 1853, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. For piano. Other title: Blackbird quadrilles Color title page illustration: a black bird sitting on a branch with red berries / lithographed by Stannard and Dixon. (Box 2, Item 063)
  - Lloyd, Arthur, 1840-1904 Song of songs Arthur Lloyd's Song of songs, 1865, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): H. D'Alcorn For voice and piano. "Written, composed, and sung by the author at the Oxford and Canterbury music halls". Color title page illustration: portrait of Arthur Lloyd, the composer and singer / Concanen, Lee, and Siebe. (Box 2, Item 064)
  - Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869 Heinzelmännchen Heinzelmännchen, op. 83, 1842, 1 score (15 pages); Berlin (Germany): Ed. Bote and G. Bock For voice and piano. Lyricist: Kopisch, August, 1799-1853 (Box 2, Item 065)
  - Loewe, Carl, 1796-1869 In die Ferne In die Ferne, 1844, 1 score (9 pages); Leipzig (Germany): Fr. Hofmeister For voice and piano. Lyricist: Kletke, H. (Hermann), 1813-1886 First page notes that there are two editions available, "Für Sopran oder Tenor" and "Für Alt oder Bariton". First page notes this edition is "Für Sopran oder Tenor". (Box 2, Item 066)
  - Lombardini, G. Fidanzata Fidanzata: romanza, 1865, 1 score (4 pages); Naples (Italy): R. Stabilimento Ricordi For voice and piano. Lyricist: Jadelli, Luigi "Alla gentile Signora Emma Jannazzi". *date undetermined (Box 2, Item 067)
  - Lombardini, G. Fraschetta Musica per camera: la fraschetta, between 1860-1888, 1 score (9 pages); Naples (Italy): R. Stabilimento Ricordi For voice and piano. Lyricist: Indelli, L. (Box 2, Item 068)
    Title page contains contents of the "Musica per camera" collection, broken into two sections labelled "Pezzi a soli" [pieces for solo voice] and "Pezzi a più voci" [pieces for more voices]. This selection is from "Pezzi a soli" [pieces for solo voice].
  - Lombardini, G. Sorriso Sorriso: melodia, 1865, 1 score (3 pages); Milan (Italy): Tito di G. Ricordi For voice and piano. Lyricist: Oddone, Pietro "Al distintissimo Francesco Oliva Barone di Ragusa". (Box 2, Item 069)
  - Majocchi, Antonio Anacreontica Anacreontica, 1888, 1 score (5 pages); Milan (Italy): Edizioni ricordi For voice and piano. Lyricist: Vittorelli, Jacopo, 1749-1835 Title page notes this edition is for "soprano o tenore". 2nd edition. "All'Illusa. Signora Contessa Emilia Scribani Affatticati Distinta Dilettante di musica". (Box 2, Item 070)
  - Majocchi, Luigi Cieca che vende fiori Cieca che vende fiori: arietta, between 1808 and 1853, 1 score (3 pages); Milan (Italy): Giovanni Ricordi For voice and piano. "Alla Signora Marchesa Carolina d'Adda nata Marchesa Cusani". (Box 2, Item 071)
  - Malipiero, Francesco, 1824-1887 Romanza Romanza, 1848, 1 score (5 pages); Milan (Italy): R. Stabilimento Musicale Ricordi For voice and piano. Other title: Si, amici, noi partiam "All'Egregio Tenore Antonio Palma" and "Offre l'Amico Giovanni Durazzo". (Box 2, Item 072)
  - Malipiero, Francesco, 1824-1887 Serenata Serenata, 1842, 1 score (3 pages); Naples (Italy): Stabilimento Ricordi For voice and piano. Other title: A quel raggio increato che brilla Title page notes "Per voce di Soprano". "Dedicate all'Esimia Dilettante La Nobile Signora Bianca Caffi". *date undetermined (Box 3, Item 073)
  - Marschner, Heinrich, 1795-1861 Junge Lieder, op. 129. Den Zweig an den Hut Junge Lieder: den Zweig an den Hut, op. 129 no. 1, circa 1850, 1 score (9 pages); Dresden (Germany): Wilhelm Paul For voice and piano. Lyricist: Müller, Wolfgang Other title: Den Zweig an den Hut Title page notes this edition is for "Tenor oder Sopran". Title page illustration: floral filigree illuminating title. (Box 3, Item 074)
    Five other titles of op. 129 listed on title page.
  - Masini, F. (Francesco), 1804-1863 Novice du carmel Dilettante: la novice du carmel: romance, 1842, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Jourdain, Laure Other title: Dilettante, no. 29 Title page illustration: a young woman in plainclothes being welcomed into a convent by nuns. (Box 3, Item 075)
    Additional verse notated without music on the final page.
  - Masini, F. (Francesco), 1804-1863 Papillon Papillon: chansonnette, circa 1820, 1 score (3 pages); Hague (Netherlands): F. J. Weygand For voice and piano. Lyricist: Crevel de Charlemagne, Louis, 1806- (Box 3, Item 076)
  - Masini, F. (Francesco), 1804-1863 Silvio Pellico Silvio Pellico au Spielberg, 1858, 1 score (3 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott For voice and piano. Lyricist: Barateau, Emile Other title: Lyre française, no. 166 Title page illustration: a portrait of Silvio Pellico in prison at Speilberg. (Box 3, Item 077)
    Additional verse notated without music on the final page. Bound with: Brutus: chant pour voix de basse / paroles de E. Plouvier; musique de J. Concone.
  - Masini, F. (Francesco), 1804-1863 Vent d'orage Dilettante: le vent d'orage: romance, 1842, 1 score (3 pages); Brussels (Belgium): J. E. Libau For voice and piano. Lyricist: Carrié, Aricie Other title: Dilettante, no. 26 Title page illustration: a man waving his hat and getting off of a small boat onto shore. (Box 3, Item 078)
  - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 Lieder, men's voices, op. 50. Jäger Abschied; arranged Jägers Abschied, circa 1870, 1 score (6 pages); Unidentified: Unidentified For piano. Arranger: Friedrich, F. Arranged by F. Friedrich and listed as his op. 82. Plate number E.B. 72. "Dem Fräulein Ida Jafée". *no date, publisher, or country info Title page illustration: a portrait of Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy. (Box 3, Item 079)
  - Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864 Prophète. Donnez pour une pauvre âme; arranged Prophète: opéra en cinq acts: Complainte de la mendiante, circa 1860, 1 score (7 pages); Paris (France): Brandus et Cie. For voice and piano. Lyricist: Scribe, Eugène, 1791-1861 Arranger: Garaudé, Alexis de, 1821-1854 Other title: No. 17 bis Le Prophète Title page notes the opera was arranged for piano. First page notes the piece is "transposée pour voix de soprano". "Chantée par Mme. Viardot". (Box 3, Item 080)
    Thematic index of the sections of the opera on title page.
  - Morasca, Benedetto Rosa Rosa: Siciliana, 1891, 1 score (7 pages); Palermo (Italy): Edizioni Giorgio Sulli For voice and piano. Lyricist: Pelaez, A. "Alle Mie Sorelle Fanny e Ninetta". Title page illustration: floral filigree illuminating title, with a vignette of a woman in traditional dress. (Box 3, Item 081)
    First page contains text of poem by itself, with the Sicilian text by A. Pelaez and "traduzione ritmica italiana" by Cav. F. De Beaumont.
  - Mullen, Alfred Pet of the family Pet of the family: valse facile, circa 1890, 1 score (2 pages); London (England): B. Williams For piano. Possibly incomplete. The music is marked as No. 1. Jenny Jones. Color title page illustration: a little girl in a red dress and bonnet hugging a lamb with a red bandana around its neck. (Box 3, Item 082)
  - Nägeli, Hans Georg, 1773-1836 Freut euch des Lebens Gesellschaftslied, circa 1800, 1 score (4 pages); Berlin (Germany): J. J. Hummel For choir and piano. The song setting (attributed to Nägeli)--is followed by a set of theme and variations for piano by Mozart (Variationen über Freut euch des Lebens) based on the same tune. (Box 3, Item 083)
    Additional verses notated without music on the first page.
  - Nelson, S. (Sydney), 1800-1862 Lass o' Gowrie Lass of Gowrie, between 1836-1840, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Jefferys and Co. For voice and piano. Title page illustration: a couple in traditional Scottish dress / J. Graf. (Box 3, Item 084)
    Title page contains text of the chorus written as a poem.
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816 Locanda. Tutto da voi dipende; arranged Tutto da voi dipende: the celebrated duetto sung with universal applause by Sigr. Lazzarini and Sigr. Casentini at the King's Theatre, Pantheon in the comic opera of La Locanda, 1791, 1 score (8 pages); London (England): Goulding and Co. For two voices and piano. Lyricist: Bertati, Giovanni, 1735-1815 (Box 3, Item 085)
  - Paisiello, Giovanni, 1740-1816 Nina. Son gia tuo bell'idol mio; arranged Son gia tuo bell'idol mio: terzetto in the opera of Nina, and sung by Sigra. Banti, Sigr. Viganoni, and Sigr. Rovedino, 1791, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Rt. Birchall For three voices and piano. (Box 3, Item 086)
  - Parry, John, 1776-1851 Royal Cambrian quadrilles Royal Cambrian quadrilles, 1822, 1 score (11 pages); London (England): J. Power For flute and piano. "Respectfully dedicated to Lady H. Williams Wynn". First page is an advertisement for other pieces from the same publisher. Dance instructions are included. Title page illustration: a crown with feathers coming up through it / engraved by R. and E. Williamson. (Box 3, Item 087)
    No. 1 Arthur -- No. 2 Caradog -- No. 3 Madog -- No. 4 Glyndwr -- No. 5 Llywelyn.
  - Perronnet, Amélie, 1838-1901 C'était bon dans l'ancien temps C'était bon dans l'ancien temps, 1856, 1 score (4 pages); Paris (France): Au Ménestrel For voice and piano. First page notes that there are two editions available, "No. 1. Baryton ou contralto" and "No. 2. Ténor ou soprano". First page notes this edition is for "No. 2. Ténor ou soprano". "A Mme. Wekerlin Damoreau". Title page illustration: two women, one in a black cloak and head covering and one in a white dress with hair decorations, stand outside / A. Jorel. (Box 3, Item 088)
  - Pohlenz, August Kleine Tambour Kleine Tambour, circa 1830, 1 score (3 pages); Berlin (Germany): Self published For voice and piano. Lyricist: Gerhard, Wilhelm, 1780-1858 Title page notes the piece is dedicated to "seinem Freunde Albert Hering". *published "auf Kosten des Komponisten" [at the expense of the composer] - how do we list publisher and location for these pieces? (Box 3, Item 089)
  - Portugal, Marcos Antônio da Fonseca, 1762-1830 Fernando nel Messico. Rendimi il figlio o barbaro; arranged Rendimi il figlio o barbaro: the favorite duet sung by Mrs. Billington and Sigr. Viganoni in the opera of Fernando in Mexico, circa 1800, 1 score (10 pages); London (England): Rt. Birchall For two voices and piano. Lyricist: Diodati, Giuseppe Maria (Box 1, Item 090)
  - Pridham, John, 1818-1896 Wayside sketches. Cottage by the stream Wayside sketches, no. 11: the cottage by the stream: valsette, 1877, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Evans and Co. For piano. Color title page illustration: a cottage on a river with a bridge in the background / R. J. Hamerton. (Box 3, Item 091)
  - Pridham, John, 1818-1896 Wayside sketches. Rustic porch Wayside sketches, no. 10: the rustic porch: melody, 1877, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Evans and Co. For piano. Color title page illustration: a family and small dog outside on the porch of a house / R. J. Hamerton. (Box 3, Item 092)
  - Pridham, John, 1818-1896 When Johnny comes marching home When Johnny comes marching home: polka, 1867, 1 score (6 pages); London (England): Brewer and Co. For piano. Title page illustration: a town welcoming home several soldiers on horseback / J. W. Lee. (Box 3, Item 093)
  - Proch, Heinrich Liebesbothe Liebesbothe, 1839, 1 score (7 pages); Vienna (Austria): Ant. Diabelli und Comp. For voice and piano. Lyricist: Markbreiter, Moritz Title page illustration: filigree illuminating title with a star above the text. (Box 3, Item 094)
  - Proch, Heinrich Wanderlied Wanderlied an Sie!, 1839, 1 score (11 pages); Vienna (Austria): A. Diabelli For voice, with piano and waldhorns. Lyricist: Saphir, Moritz Gottlieb, 1795-1858 First page notes that there are two editions available, "f. Alt od. Bariton m. Pforte allein" and "f. Sopr. od. Tenor m. Pf. all.". First page notes this edition is "f. Sopr. Od. Tenor m. Pf. all.". Title page: or for viola, or violoncello, or piano alone. Title page illustration: filigree illuminating title. (Box 3, Item 095)
  - Puget, Loïsa, 1810-1889 Épis d'or Épis d'or: recueil de chant: six mélodies, 1848, 1 score (12 pages); Paris (France): Bureau de la France Musicale For voice, and 2 voices and piano. At head of title: 1848. Aux abonnés de La France musicale. Additional verses are notated without piano music on the final page of each selection. Title page illustration: filigree illuminating title / A. Lafont. (Box 3, Item 096)
    No. 1. Marie -- No. 2. L'Enfant -- No. 3. Pied d'amour -- No. 4. La touriere -- No. 5. Tous ne m'aimee plus -- No. 6. Les joutes sur l'eau.
  - Purcell, Henry, 1659-1695 Tempest. Full fathom five; arranged Full fathom five: sung in The Tempest, circa 1800, 1 score (2 pages); Unidentified: Unidentified For voice and piano and for chorus. Lyricist: Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 Keyboard part includes figures. (Box 3, Item 097)
  - Quidant, A. (Alfred), 1815-1893 Grande Etude-Galop Grande Etude-Galop: morceau de concert, op. 21, circa 1851, 1 score (9 pages); Milan (Italy): Jean Ricordi For piano. "A son ami E. Prudent." "Executee par Adolphe Fumagalli dans ses concerts". (Box 3, Item 098)
    Piece is bound in a blue cover labelled "Grande Galoppo di Quidant." in handwriting, and signed with an illegible name.
  - Read, Ezra, 1862-1922 Don't tease Don't tease: schottische, 1897, 1 score (7 pages); London (England): J. Williams For piano. Title page illustration: a young boy and girl sit on a couch with a small dog / Stannard and Son. (Box 3, Item 099)
  - Reed, Thomas German, 1817-1888 I'm a young man from the country; arranged I'm a young man from the country - but you don't get over me, circa 1865, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): H. D'Alcorn For voice and piano. Arranger: Sydney, Harry "The original melody of this song is known as The Young man from the country, composed by German Reed." Pages cropped causing loss of publisher statement. Identification based on plate number: H. D. 267. "Written and sung by Mr. Harry Sydney at the London and provincial concerts, also by Mr. W. Randall". Color title page illustration: a portrait of a Harry Sydney standing in a green coat with riding crop / fm. Photo by Hobcraft; Concanen and Lee. (Box 3, Item 100)
  - Reissiger, Friedrich August, 1809-1883 Lieder, op. 48 Zwei Lieder, op. 48: Entschuldigung; Liebessuchen, circa 1841, 1 score (5 pages); Leipzig (Germany): Friedrich Hofmeister For voice and piano. Lyricist: Reinick, Robert, 1805-1852 and Keil, Johann Georg, 1781-1857 (Box 3, Item 101)
    Entschuldigung (with lyrics by Robert Reinick) -- Liebessuchen (with lyrics by Johann Georg Keil).
  - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868 Barbiere di Siviglia. Voce poco fa; arranged Erinnerung an Sabina Heinefetter: Cavatine A. D. Oper der Barbier von Sevilla, 1816, 1 score (3 pages); Heidelberg (Germany): Wilh. Thiese For piano. Arranger: Faulhaber, K. Title page illustration: a portrait of Sabina Heinefetter. (Box 3, Item 102)
  - Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894 Mädchens Abendgedanken Mädchens Abendgedanken, 1882, 1 score (3 pages); Berlin (Germany): Ed. Bote and G. Bock For voice and piano. Lyricist: Vischer, Friedrich Theodor, 1807-1887 Dedicated to Fräulein Ottilie Otticker. Color title page illustration: vignettes of flowers, cherubim, and a couple dancing and getting married / C. G. Röder. (Box 3, Item 103)
  - Rummel, Joseph, 1818-1880 Schwalbacher-Polka Rheinlaender: Sammlung beliebter Polkas, Galoppen für das Pianoforte. No. 132: Schwalbacher-Polka, 1852, 1 score (3 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott's Söhnen For piano. Title page illustration: countryside scene with trees, fields, and various people. (Box 3, Item 104)
    Title page contains the contents of the Die Rheinlaender collection, numbered 121 through 132.
  - Russell, Henry, 1812-1900 I'm afloat, I'm afloat I'm afloat, I'm afloat: No. [1] of Two sea songs, 1842, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Duff and Hodgson For voice and piano. Lyricist: Cook, Eliza, 1818-1889 Title page illustration: a sailboat at sea / C. Graf. (Box 4, Item 105)
  - Schubert, Camille, 1810-1889 Lancers Lancers = Lanciers: célèbre quadrille anglais pour piano, between 1857 and 1885, 1 score (6 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott's Söhne For piano. Directions for the dances in French included on cover verso. "Edition avec theorie d'apres les plus celebres professeurs de Londres". Title page illustration: mounted lancers riding towards right in a field. (Box 4, Item 106)
    No. 1. La dorset ou Les tiroirs -- No. 2. Les lignes ou Lodoïska --No. 3. Les moulinets ou La native -- No. 4. Les visites -- No. 5. Les lanciers -- No. 4bis. Les graces.
  - Scott, Bennett, 1875-1930 Lot 99 Lot 99, 1898, 1 score (4 pages); London (England): Francis, Day and Hunter For voice and piano. Lyricist: Cotes, C. G. "Sung by Miss Rose Harvey". Color title page illustration: vignettes of a woman on a lounge chair, a woman at a podium, and a man with a cane captioned with various text / H. G. Banks. (Box 4, Item 107)
  - Smallwood, William Little Bo-Peep Little Bo-Peep: polka, 1874, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Brewer and Co. For piano. Color title page illustration: a woman with a red scarf around her waist and a picnic basket sitting on a bench and smiling at a child in the forest / Stannard and Co. (Box 4, Item 108)
  - Smallwood, William Sea shells polka Sea shells polka, between 1880 and 1889, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): B. Williams For piano. Color title page illustration: various brightly colored seashells with the sea and night in the background / Tracker. (Box 4, Item 109)
  - Smallwood, William Village féte polka Village féte polka, circa 1880, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): Brewer and Co. For piano. Color title page illustration: people dancing in a village center / J. A. Jennings. (Box 4, Item 110)
  - Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895 Gedichte in der österreichischen Volksmundart, op. 32 Zwei Gedichte in der österreichischen Volksmundart, 1847, 1 score (7 pages); Vienna (Austria): Tobias Haslinger's Witwe und Sohn For voice and piano. Lyricist: Klesheim, Anton, Freiherr von, 1816?-1884 Title page notes the piece was originally performed by "der Künstlerin Mathilde Helwig". (Box 4, Item 111)
    's Deanderl ám Bach -- Was is á Wundá?.
  - Sydney, Harry Free and easy Free and easy, circa 1870, 1 score (4 pages); London (England): B. Williams For voice and piano. Color title page illustration: a portrait of Harry Sydney with colorful clothes sitting on a chair. (Box 4, Item 112)
  - Széchényi, Imre, gróf, 1825-1898 Tulipe Tulipe = Die Tulpe: mazurka, 1855, 1 score (3 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott For piano. Color title page illustration: a red and blue striped tulip on a green stem. (Box 4, Item 113)
  - Thomas, J. R. (John Rogers), 1830-1896 Cottage by the sea No. 67 of Christy's Minstrels songs as sung by them: The cottage by the sea, circa 1865, 1 score (5 pages); London (England): B. Williams For voice and piano. Title page illustration: signatures of the Christy's Minstrels (captioned "All the genuine Editions bear their Signatures"). (Box 4, Item 114)
    Title page lists contents of the Christy's Minstrels songs collection, number 1 through 86.
  - Unidentified Five favorite dances Five favorite dances. No. 38, between 1810 and 1812, 1 score (2 pages); London (England): W. Andrews For piano. Caption title specifies that the piece is for piano or violin. (Box 4, Item 115)
    The Bath Waltz -- Lord St. Orville -- Le Bourbon -- L'Angouleme -- The Legacy.
  - Vandervell, Willem Immer wieder; arranged Immer wieder = Always again: gavotte, circa 1900, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Bayley and Ferguson For piano 4-hands. (Box 4, Item 116)
  - Voss, Charles, 1815-1882 Chansons anglaises, piano, op. 238. Annie Laurie Chansons anglaises, op. 238. No. 3: Annie Laurie, circa 1860, 1 score (7 pages); Offenbach am Main (Germany): Jean André For piano. Color title page illustration: a red, white, and blue flag being held the figure of Britannia. (Box 4, Item 117)
    Title page lists the contents of the Op. 238 collection.
  - Wallace, William Vincent, 1812-1865 Grande mazurka guerrière Grande mazurka guerrière, 1856, 1 score (9 pages); London (England): Robert Cocks and Co. For piano. At head of title: "À Sa Majesté l'Impératrice des Français". American publications used the title Eugenie, grande mazurka guerriere. Title page illustration: the crown and heraldic symbols of Empress Eugenie, wife of Napoleon / Stannard and Dixon. (Box 4, Item 118)
  - Wallerstein, A. (Anton), 1813-1892 Garde mobile polka; arranged Danses Élégantes, no. 2: La garde mobile: polka, 1869, 1 score (7 pages); Mainz (Germany): B. Schott For piano 4-hands. Other title: Sieges-polka, op. 37 Title page illustration: vignettes illustrating the titles of the three dances: a woman in formal dress, La garde mobile troops, and people riding on a steam engine. (Box 4, Item 119)
    Title page contains the contents of the Danses Élégantes collection, labelled as "No. 1. La coquette, polka (priska-polka)" [No. 1. The coquette (priska-polka)], "No. 2. La garde mobile, polka (sieges-polka)" [No. 2. The mobile guard, polka (sieges-polka)], and "No. 3. Le train de plaisir, polka de carneval (jahrmarkts-polka)" [No. 3. The train of pleasure, polka (jahrmarkts-polka)].